MIKE DENTON

PROFILE

I'm a UX designer. I love making difficult things fun and easy to use. Over the last 10 years I've lead the design of major projects at Geckoboard, Xero, and Mitsubishi Electric. I love collaborating with others and sharing my passion for design. After some time off traveling I'm returning to NZ and keen to take on my next challenge.

CONTACT

www.mikedenton.design
email@michaeldenton.co.nz
linkedin.com/in/mike-denton

NZ: +64 274644915

UK: +44 7810535294

EXPERIENCE

Geckoboard • Lead UX Designer 2017-19

At Geckoboard I led design efforts to improve the product for new users. Various changes helped improve the experience and increased the likelihood that trialists would buy the product.

- Uncovered major friction points by conducting user research.
- · Reduced the time it takes new customers to get set up.
- · Redesigned the dashboard editing experience.
- · Gained a deep understanding of business metrics.

Xero • Senior Product Designer 2012-17

At Xero I led the redesign of Xero's financial reporting tools. I worked closely with agile software teams to help them learn more about their customers, explore design solutions, and build a quality product.

- · Led the redesign of Xero's financial reporting tools.
- · Conducted foundation research into how customers track their finances.
- Designed an online editor for accountants producing financial documents.
- Designed tools to automatically file sales tax and other forms online.

Mitsubishi Electric • Graphic Designer 2011-12

At Mitsubishi Electric I led the redesign of their website and created marketing material to promote the brand and its products.

- · Led the redesign of mitsubishi-electric.co.nz
- · Produced a industry magazine and various product catalogues.
- Created advertisements for magazines, billboards and point of sale.

Self-Employed • Web Designer 2010-11

As a self employed web designer I meet directly with clients, designed marketing material and built simple websites. My clients including a lawn mowing company, a legal service, and a student mentoring service.

· Designing and building simple websites for clients.

SKILLS

User Research

- · Usability Testing
- · Customer Interviews
- · Experience Mapping
- · Data & Analytics

Design

- User Objectives
- · Interface Design
- · Content & Structure
- · Internal Communication

Prototyping

- Wireframing
- · Visual Mockups
- · Sketch / Adobe
- · HTML / Javascript

EDUCATION

Master of Design

User Centered Design Massey University, 2010

Bachelor of Design

Visual Communication Massey University, 2008